<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://www.cambridgerefugees.org//feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://www.cambridgerefugees.org//" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2024-07-15T19:35:42+00:00</updated><id>https://www.cambridgerefugees.org//feed.xml</id><title type="html">Cambridge Refugee Resettlement Campaign</title><subtitle>Cambridge Refugee Resettlement Campaign helps those who have arrived in Cambridge seeking safety, in all ways from the practical provision of clothes and furniture, to helping with language learning and social differences.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Refugee Week 2024 - Art Festival</title><link href="https://www.cambridgerefugees.org//newslist/2024/06/17/refugee-week-art-festival.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Refugee Week 2024 - Art Festival" /><published>2024-06-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-06-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.cambridgerefugees.org//newslist/2024/06/17/refugee-week-art-festival</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.cambridgerefugees.org//newslist/2024/06/17/refugee-week-art-festival.html">&lt;p&gt;This year, World Refugee Day is 20 June, and there are a number of events happening in Cambridge to help us celebrate and learn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Arts Festival is open 11am to 4pm at the Alison Building, 7 West Road, on Saturday 22 June.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2024-06-17-RefugeeArtsWkPoster.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Collage poster for Refugee Week Art Festival 2024&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="newslist" /><summary type="html">This year, World Refugee Day is 20 June, and there are a number of events happening in Cambridge to help us celebrate and learn.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Voices of Hope and Compassion</title><link href="https://www.cambridgerefugees.org//newslist/2024/06/17/refugee-week-rosen.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Voices of Hope and Compassion" /><published>2024-06-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-06-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.cambridgerefugees.org//newslist/2024/06/17/refugee-week-rosen</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.cambridgerefugees.org//newslist/2024/06/17/refugee-week-rosen.html">&lt;p&gt;This year, World Refugee Day is 20 June, and there are a number of events happening in Cambridge to help us celebrate and learn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Sunday 30 June at the Cambridge Corn Exchange, from 4-5:30pm, there is a free concert in support of refugees. The concert is hosted by Michael Rosen, alongside choirs, poets, musicians, dance groups and more, from across Cambridge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2024-06-17-concert.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Poster for Voices of Hope and Compassion concert, featuring Michael Rosen, along with the text already outlined&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="newslist" /><summary type="html">This year, World Refugee Day is 20 June, and there are a number of events happening in Cambridge to help us celebrate and learn.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Refugee Week 2024 - Conference</title><link href="https://www.cambridgerefugees.org//newslist/2024/06/17/refugee-week-conference.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Refugee Week 2024 - Conference" /><published>2024-06-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-06-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.cambridgerefugees.org//newslist/2024/06/17/refugee-week-conference</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.cambridgerefugees.org//newslist/2024/06/17/refugee-week-conference.html">&lt;p&gt;This year, World Refugee Day is 20 June, and there are a number of events happening in Cambridge to help us celebrate and learn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Conference is open 10am to 6pm at the Alison Building, 7 West Road, on Thursday 20 June.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2024-06-17-refugee-week-conference.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Collage poster for Refugee Week Conference 2024&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="newslist" /><summary type="html">This year, World Refugee Day is 20 June, and there are a number of events happening in Cambridge to help us celebrate and learn.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Annual report for 2023</title><link href="https://www.cambridgerefugees.org//newslist/2024/05/20/annual-report-for-2023.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Annual report for 2023" /><published>2024-05-20T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-05-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.cambridgerefugees.org//newslist/2024/05/20/annual-report-for-2023</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.cambridgerefugees.org//newslist/2024/05/20/annual-report-for-2023.html">&lt;p&gt;You can now &lt;a href=&quot;/files/2023-06-30-crrc-annual-report.pdf&quot;&gt;download&lt;/a&gt; (10.5 MB PDF file) our full annual report for the year to June 2023.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CRRC could not carry out its work without the tremendous contributions from its many volunteers and supporters. CRRC works in a collaborative manner, recognising that the nature of a volunteer-led group requires flexibility, whilst ensuring that it fulfils tasks that it commits to, within given timeframes to achieve its objectives. The organisation actively seeks and values volunteers from diverse backgrounds, life experiences and perspectives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There has been a high level of ongoing engagement from potential volunteers getting in touch with CRRC to express their interest in being involved, suggesting that the operational model is effective.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Between July 2022 and June 2023, 29 new volunteers joined CRRC to take up a range of roles. The team completed basic and enhanced DBS checks for these volunteers, in line with UK Government requirements and according to their role. At the end of the financial year, CRRC had over 161 active volunteers, as well as further excellent applicants waiting for potential opportunities. The huge number of volunteer hours provided, and level of enthusiasm and dedication shown by our volunteers form a vital part of the CRRC community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Several volunteer gatherings took place to allow volunteers to exchange ideas, and to introduce prospective volunteers to understand their potential role prior to signing up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/files/2023-06-30-crrc-annual-report.pdf&quot;&gt;Read the full annual report for 2023 »&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="newslist" /><summary type="html">You can now download (10.5 MB PDF file) our full annual report for the year to June 2023.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Refugee Week 2024</title><link href="https://www.cambridgerefugees.org//newslist/2024/05/19/refugee-week.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Refugee Week 2024" /><published>2024-05-19T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-05-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.cambridgerefugees.org//newslist/2024/05/19/refugee-week</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.cambridgerefugees.org//newslist/2024/05/19/refugee-week.html">&lt;p&gt;This year, World Refugee Day is 20 June, and there are a number of events happening in Cambridge to help us celebrate and learn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At time of writing, we know of two events. First, there’s a conference on 20 June itself. It’s being advertised as:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;an engaging programme of research and public events including research panels and flash talks. Bringing together a diverse array of academics, activists and community members, this event is open to all. It engages with the diversity of refugee experiences in an effort to uphold refugee rights. Free and all welcome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Saturday 22 June, there’s an event “Celebration, Arts, Refugees”:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;A family day, with musical performances, ceramic arts, visual arts and films and documentaries. It engages with the diversity of refugee experiences in an effort to uphold refugee rights. This day is in celebration of and with those in exile. The event is free and all welcome (including children).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For full details, and in particular for the up-to-date details, visit the University of Cambridge’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.humanmovement.cam.ac.uk/events/cambridge-refugee-week-2024&quot;&gt;Refugee Hub&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="newslist" /><summary type="html">This year, World Refugee Day is 20 June, and there are a number of events happening in Cambridge to help us celebrate and learn.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Treasurer</title><link href="https://www.cambridgerefugees.org//jobs/2024/04/09/job-treasurer.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Treasurer" /><published>2024-04-09T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-04-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.cambridgerefugees.org//jobs/2024/04/09/job-treasurer</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.cambridgerefugees.org//jobs/2024/04/09/job-treasurer.html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;introduction&quot;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CRRC is a &lt;a href=&quot;https://register-of-charities.charitycommission.gov.uk/charity-search/-/charity-details/5095939&quot;&gt;registered charity&lt;/a&gt; with the primary object of supporting refugees and displaced persons in Cambridge and Cambridgeshire. The charity is lead by the Board of Trustees of which the Treasurer is an ex-officio member. (S)he is subject to the decisions of the Board.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-role&quot;&gt;The role&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Treasurer will hold the CRRC’s Trustees to account for the Charity’s finances and vision, maintain financial control and ensure we comply with our legal responsibilities as a Registered Charity. The Treasurer will work with all members of the team to ensure that there is a transparent and clear financial process. As Treasurer to the Charity, you will also become a Trustee. Trustees are expected to understand and accept the legal duties, responsibilities and liabilities of trusteeship and understand their role as a Trustee.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The role is mainly online with occasional in person meetings in Cambridge. The expected hours will vary between 2 to 6 hours per week with a flexible working arrangement. The position is unpaid. Expenses incurred in undertaking the role will be reimbursed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A competent treasurer or part-qualified bookkeeper or accountant would be ideal. Experience in the charity field is desirable but not essential.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our bank is the Co-operative Bank. There is no branch in Cambridge, so all transactions are electronic or by post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-duties-of-the-treasurer&quot;&gt;The duties of the Treasurer&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Budgets&lt;/em&gt; The Treasurer co-ordinates the production of an annual budget, in conjunction with Group leaders.  Details are kept on excel spreadsheets.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Financial Reports&lt;/em&gt; will be presented to the Board every quarter, setting out the income, expenditure and balance against budget at the end of each quarter. In addition to providing the Board with an overview of the financial position of CRRC, these reports should help the Board to understand trends and pressures and help the Board to understand how CRRC is using funds to support its objective.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Financial records&lt;/em&gt; These are now only kept electronically, using excel spreadsheets. The existing spreadsheets have been set up by the present Treasurer, but could be modified if improvements are considered advantageous.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Receipts&lt;/em&gt; are from various sources, as standing orders, bank transfers, cheques and through Kindlink, Paypal, CAF and payroll deductions. Cash is rarely used.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Gift Aid&lt;/em&gt; The treasurer is responsible for making claims for Gift Aid and for keeping Gift Aid forms.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Payments&lt;/em&gt; All payments must have signed off by a Trustee responsible for the budget heading. The vast majority are by bank transfer.  Claims for payment are made on an electronic form to the Treasurer, who then sets up a bank transfer which is forwarded to the signatories for approval.  This gives final authorisation for the bank transfer to take place.  The Treasurer must check that the form is correctly filled in and the payment requested is in line with relevant e-mails and overall CRRC policy. A bank card is used for a limited number of specific payments. The number of payments varies each month. In 2022-23 there were 270 payments across the year.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Restricted and designated funds&lt;/em&gt; In addition to the main CRRC fund, there are currently 3 restricted/designated funds.  These funds use the same bank account, but its transactions are recorded separately.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Annual accounts&lt;/em&gt; The Treasurer is responsible for producing annual accounts after the end of the financial year, which runs from 1 July to 30 June.  These are then presented in draft to the Board before being submitted to an Independent Examiner.  The Treasurer then passes the approved annual account summary to the relevant Trustee for submission to the Charity Commission (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cambridgerefugees.org/newslist/2023/12/29/annual-report-for-2022.html&quot;&gt;Annual report and financial accounts 2022&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Financial policy and Procedures&lt;/em&gt; This document gives in more detail the above information.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Supporting volunteers&lt;/em&gt; The Treasurer is also responsible for informing volunteers about the process for payments, including through relevant updates to process documents, and may be required from time to time to contribute to updated guidance for volunteers.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;additional-notes&quot;&gt;Additional notes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The current treasurer will be training the new treasurer and will remain available to support the new treasurer. The main reason for the stepping back of the current treasurer is to make time for the current treasurer to drive and oversee important changes and adaptations to facilitate the financial management of CRRC and to be more closely involved in the overall governance of our charity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CRRC intends to adopt a digital payments system in 2024-25, in order to streamline the payment process for CRRC’s volunteers, budget approvers, bank signatories, and for the Treasurer. CRRC is also exploring changing the bank account.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is possible that the number of restricted/designated bank accounts may be reduced.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-to-apply&quot;&gt;How to apply&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Applications &lt;strong&gt;must&lt;/strong&gt; be made by email to &lt;a href=&quot;admin@cambridgerefugees.org&quot;&gt;admin@cambridgerefugees.org&lt;/a&gt; in the first instance; please ignore the template “Apply now” button below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please provide your CV including the names and contact details of two references, along with a covering letter stating why you wish to work for the organisation, how your skills would add value to the board and any other relevant information.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="jobs" /><summary type="html">Introduction</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Focal point family support worker</title><link href="https://www.cambridgerefugees.org//jobs/2024/03/08/focal-point-family-support-worker.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Focal point family support worker" /><published>2024-03-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-03-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.cambridgerefugees.org//jobs/2024/03/08/focal-point-family-support-worker</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.cambridgerefugees.org//jobs/2024/03/08/focal-point-family-support-worker.html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-is-a-focal-point&quot;&gt;What is a ‘focal point’?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a pivotal role that provides a link between a designated refugee family and members of the family support team and/or CRRC committee. It is similar to being a family support worker but it can cross over into a befriending role. The focal point often visits the family in their home and is there to help or advise on a wide variety of life issues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The focal point works as part of the family support team, raising urgent issues as required and providing regular monthly reports to the wider team. There may also be a team of focal points where the family needs are greater.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-much-time-does-it-take&quot;&gt;How much time does it take?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This varies with each family’s needs and with your own personal time availability.  We aim to encourage you to communicate with your family every week or two, either a visit to their home or a phone call.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;main-aims-and-intentions-of-the-focal-point&quot;&gt;Main aims and intentions of the focal point&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The overall role of the focal point is to find ways of both assisting and empowering the resettled family to be able to more easily and comfortably settle into the UK as their new home. This has and could include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;finding out what the family needs to make their home comfortable with their essential needs and some luxury needs met.  See donations;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;checking that the children have places in local schools and helping them with school or college applications, school uniforms and sometimes communication with the school;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;supporting family members in making sure that they can access medical care (e.g. local GP surgeries and dental practices); some focal points offer lifts to appointments but others do not;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;politely finding out if the family needs any help with budgeting, paying bills, getting internet connections organised or TV licences.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;acting as a communication link between CRRC and the family, letting the family know about what services and activities CRRC is offering;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;providing regular updates to CRRC if anything big changes (from children having problems at school or receiving awards, anyone being in hospital or if essential white goods such as a washing machine or fridge breaks down);&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;alerting the family support team to any concerns or problems the family may be facing that you think CRRC could help with or help advise you or them with.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-sort-of-things-will-i-help-with&quot;&gt;What sort of things will I help with?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Be a friendly face and get to know the family and their interests, their hopes for the future.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Discover what they like to do, their hobbies, their education or job plans.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Find out if they have any problems with neighbours, schools and provide practical and emotional support.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sometimes we need to refer a family to social services so that they can provide their professional help. This is their professional job and the focal point needs to know their own limits.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="jobs" /><summary type="html">What is a ‘focal point’?</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Childcare during English lessons</title><link href="https://www.cambridgerefugees.org//jobs/2024/02/08/job-childcare-during-english-lessons.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Childcare during English lessons" /><published>2024-02-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-02-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.cambridgerefugees.org//jobs/2024/02/08/job-childcare-during-english-lessons</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.cambridgerefugees.org//jobs/2024/02/08/job-childcare-during-english-lessons.html">&lt;p&gt;Childcare volunteers take care of under school-age children while their parents are attending to their English lessons. There are usually 2-3 childcare volunteers during each session, and the aim is to keep the children happy and occupied with play, singing and reading. We don’t do any personal care and the parents are responsible for taking care of toileting, other personal hygiene or comforting their child/children in case of any upset.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most important quality in this role is kindness. You should also be trustworthy and happy to play with children. It is important that you understand child safeguarding issues (we provide safeguarding training in induction) and all our childcare volunteers will have their DBS check before they can start with volunteering. The sessions are two hours long.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An enhanced DBS check is necessary for this role. Further information can be found &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gov.uk/government/organisations/disclosure-and-barring-service/about&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;we-hope-that-volunteering-with-us-will-benefit-you-in-a-number-of-ways&quot;&gt;We hope that volunteering with us will benefit you in a number of ways&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You will meet a group of passionate people.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You will become a part of a team.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You will develop your skills, learn new ones and gain work experience.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You will make a difference to the lives of vulnerable people.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-you-can-expect-from-us&quot;&gt;What you can expect from us&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We will:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;treat you with respect, consideration and appreciation;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;ensure you have a clear idea of what your role is and how to do it;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;provide training and support you may need to carry out your role;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;ensure your safety while volunteering for us;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;keep you updated about our activities;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;value and recognise your contribution;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;support you through regular meetings and feedback on your work;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;update you on the difference your work is making&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-we-expect-from-you&quot;&gt;What we expect from you&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We expect you to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;understand our values and behave appropriately by treating other volunteers and the people you help with respect and consideration;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;work with us to fulfill our mission and to achieve our objectives;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;be committed and reliable;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;carry out your role according to our guidelines, policies and procedures, and to the best of your ability;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;flag up any problems immediately and to the relevant person;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;attend relevant training and meetings, where needed;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;talk to us and let us know how you’re getting on;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;provide as much notice as possible if you are unable to fulfill your commitment or if you no longer wish to volunteer for us.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="jobs" /><summary type="html">Childcare volunteers take care of under school-age children while their parents are attending to their English lessons. There are usually 2-3 childcare volunteers during each session, and the aim is to keep the children happy and occupied with play, singing and reading. We don’t do any personal care and the parents are responsible for taking care of toileting, other personal hygiene or comforting their child/children in case of any upset.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">One-to-one English tuition (children)</title><link href="https://www.cambridgerefugees.org//jobs/2024/02/06/job-one-to-one-english-tuition-children.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="One-to-one English tuition (children)" /><published>2024-02-06T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-02-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.cambridgerefugees.org//jobs/2024/02/06/job-one-to-one-english-tuition-children</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.cambridgerefugees.org//jobs/2024/02/06/job-one-to-one-english-tuition-children.html">&lt;p&gt;Our one-to-one English tutors work with individual children in a family, helping with their homework, tutoring GCSEs in core subjects, monitoring their progress, and improving their English. It is very rewarding, offering an opportunity to get to know the whole family and establish a valuable connection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We ask for a minimum commitment of six months. A weekly commitment of an hour’s teaching in the home is the norm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An enhanced DBS check is necessary for this role. Further information can be found &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gov.uk/government/organisations/disclosure-and-barring-service/about&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;we-are-looking-for&quot;&gt;We are looking for:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A recognised ESOL qualification.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Patience.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Interest in working with children.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;An understanding of the national curriculum expectations would be useful but not essential.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Willingness to provide brief quarterly progress reports to the Education Group.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;in-return-youll-get-an-opportunity-to&quot;&gt;In return, you’ll get an opportunity to:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Develop your English tuition skills.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Establish a valuable connection with a refugee family.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Make a real and significant difference to the lives of refugees.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Meet a wonderful and passionate group of volunteers from the Cambridge area.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="jobs" /><summary type="html">Our one-to-one English tutors work with individual children in a family, helping with their homework, tutoring GCSEs in core subjects, monitoring their progress, and improving their English. It is very rewarding, offering an opportunity to get to know the whole family and establish a valuable connection.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">One-to-one English teaching (adults)</title><link href="https://www.cambridgerefugees.org//jobs/2024/02/06/job-english-one-to-one-teaching-adults.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="One-to-one English teaching (adults)" /><published>2024-02-06T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-02-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.cambridgerefugees.org//jobs/2024/02/06/job-english-one-to-one-teaching-adults</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.cambridgerefugees.org//jobs/2024/02/06/job-english-one-to-one-teaching-adults.html">&lt;p&gt;We are looking for one-to-one English tutors to work with individual adults in their home, helping develop their English language skills. In some cases the role may involve developing language for work, or providing linguistic support for the driving test.  It is very rewarding, offering an opportunity to get to know the whole family and establish a valuable connection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We ask for a minimum commitment of six months. A weekly commitment of an hour’s teaching in the home is the norm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An enhanced DBS check is necessary for this role. Further information can be found &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gov.uk/government/organisations/disclosure-and-barring-service/about&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;we-are-looking-for&quot;&gt;We are looking for:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A recognised ESOL qualification.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Empathy and patience.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Interest in working with adults.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Willingness to provide brief quarterly progress reports to the Education Group.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;in-return-youll-get-an-opportunity-to&quot;&gt;In return, you’ll get an opportunity to:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Develop your English tuition skills.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Establish a valuable connection with a refugee family.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Make a real and significant difference to the lives of refugees.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Meet a wonderful and passionate group of volunteers from the Cambridge area.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="jobs" /><summary type="html">We are looking for one-to-one English tutors to work with individual adults in their home, helping develop their English language skills. In some cases the role may involve developing language for work, or providing linguistic support for the driving test. It is very rewarding, offering an opportunity to get to know the whole family and establish a valuable connection.</summary></entry></feed>